[PEOPLE chattering]
[PROSTITUTE 15A]
So, how about right now?
[PROSTITUTE 15A giggles]
[PROSTITUTE 15B]
How much you got?
[POLICEMAN 15A]
Oi, no sleeping down here, miss.
[yelps]
[POLICEMAN 15A gasping]
[WILLIAM] Once again,
the victim was a prostitute.
This is the second murder
to take place in Whitechapel
and there are no suspects, yet.
"Jack the Ripper," they say?
[LOUIS] Please use this room,
Mister Bonde. After you.
[BOTH]
Huh?
Hey! What're you doin'
bargin' in here, you rascal?!
Men only, meaning women
aren't allowed!
Starting this moment,
I'll be using the room as well.
So, cheers, mate.
[gasps] Are you just
gonna stand there?
Well, considering the fact
Mister Bonde is a man,
I see no problem.
[MORAN]
Traitor!
Please, Moran.
We are no different.
And I'd like you
to treat me as such.
This doesn't make me
uncomfortable,
so pay me no mind. Deal?
Just 'cause you're fine with it
doesn't mean I have to be!
Besides,
there're other factors in play.
[BONDE]
Such as?
You may have doubts,
but I'm more than
confident in my abilities.
[MORAN]
I don't just mean appearances.
Face it--
you can't hope to match
a man's upper-body strength.
Look, you simply won't--
You don't know when to quit.
But since it appears
you're dead set
on not acknowledging who I am...
...let's test your
theory... you and I.
[MORAN whimpers]
And what is that
supposed to mean?
Test what? Keep her back!
That's quite enough shouting.
Now, what's wrong here?
Just in time!
Listen to this, William!
Go on, tell him!
Seeing as how I'm a gentleman,
I would like to use this room
with my fellow associates.
What's your take on it, Will?
Based on what I've heard,
you've some issue sharing
this space with your fellow man.
I thought this was serious.
[MORAN gasps]
After all we've been through,
you traitor.
Honestly,
you've got William twisted
around your little finger.
What exactly will it take
for you to finally
acknowledge who I am?
You've got it wrong.
The real question is
whether or not you're useful.
[WILLIAM]
Is everyone present?
I have a task I'd like
you all to work on together.
[MORAN] Together?
So... that includes her?
[WILLIAM]
We need him, yes.
Need I remind you that
you're the senior operative?
Would you show a little support?
Albert did ask you
to take charge of Bonde.
Yeah, fine. I know what he said.
[WILLIAM] The details of the job
are on this piece of paper.
I'd go over them, but at
the moment, I need to rest...
[LOUIS]
Really, Brother.
You're likely to catch a cold
if you sleep there like that.
[BONDE chuckles]
That his normal sleep routine?
It's a sort of side effect
from overexerting his mind.
When he gets this way,
he doesn't wake up for anything.
Now, concerning the
details of our mission...
- -[metal jingles]
- -[MORAN] Hm?
[MORAN]
A key?
[WOMAN 15B]
Ooh!
[WOMAN 15A] Goodness,
look at those gentlemen!
[WOMAN 15B]
My word! How handsome.
[grunts, chuckles]
[WOMAN 15C giggles]
He winked at me!
[MORAN grunts]
[MORAN]
If there was any doubt about
whether Bonde could
pass as one of us,
it's been to put rest.
[MORAN]
I'm not one to complain,
but fetching the contents of a
safe deposit box at the bank?
It's a child's errand;
why ask me?
[LOUIS]
Enough.
William ordered us all to carry
out this task, and we shall.
[MORAN]
All right, fine.
Do you always have
to be so by-the-book?
[BONDE grunts] Well, Fred.
A penny for your thoughts?
[FRED]
This assignment we're on--
William made it a point
for all of us to be involved.
It's out of the ordinary.
That's what's on my mind.
Maybe so. Still...
Regardless of what it entails,
we merely need to carry out
the task assigned to us.
[MORAN]
"The task assigned to us."
Please.
[GEOFF laughs]
Can you believe it?
I was off duty,
but Smith fell ill,
so I was given
his shift instead.
[CUSTOMER 15A]
Is that right?
It's been rough around here
lately, so I'm quite grateful.
Don't worry about a thing!
You have my word, sir!
I'll arrest any criminal
that steps through here!
[LOUIS] I need to access
my safety deposit box.
[BANK TELLER 15A] A pleasure to
see you again, Mister Moriarty.
I'll get things ready at once.
Please wait for me
in the parlor.
What's taking him?
- -[crash]
- -[CUSTOMER 15B screams]
[BANK CUSTOMERS shouting]
[CUSTOMER 15A]
Wh-Who are you people?
[BANK TELLER 15A yelps]
[ROBBER 15A] Stay calm!
No one try to be a hero!
[BANK EMPLOYEES gasp]
[ROBBER 15B] Hand over your
keys and be quick about it!
[CUSTOMERS gasp]
[ROBBER 15C]
Put those hands in the air
and stand in the
corner! Do it now!
[ROBBER 15A]
You two, take the vault.
Loot the safe deposit boxes.
And load up anything
that looks valuable.
[GEOFF] Bollocks,
that must be the leader.
I wasn't expecting a chance
at promotion to come this early.
- -[thud]
- -[GEOFF groans]
[ROBBER 15C]
You wanna live?
Stay down and shut
your mouth, yard rat!
[ROBBER 15A]
On your feet!
You and I are going
to blindfold the customers.
Look lively!
[BONDE]
What luck. A bank robbery.
Why now of all times?
We can't allow the contents
of the safe deposit box
to fall into their hands.
Also, the hostages
are a concern.
If I manage to carry out
my role well enough.
The others will accept
me as one of them.
[gasps]
[BONDE]
Where'd they go?
If they're gone, does
that mean Will's mission
takes priority
over the hostages?
I'm already
getting a late start!
[BONDE panting]
[BONDE]
What?
[BONDE (ADLER)] That certainly
didn't take long.
Where're the others?
[MORAN] Meaning what, Mister
Bonde?
The only reason I'm here
is because I had the key.
- -Huh?
- -To answer your question,
Louis and Fred are doing
their own jobs, unsupervised.
But when was the
decision made to split up?
[MORAN]
Hm? Just as I suspected.
Earlier, you said
something about
merely doing the assignment
that was given to us,
which gave me pause.
As it turns out you're a person
who takes zero initiative.
[gasps] So what
should I be doing then?
Just running off on my own?
They're two entirely
different things--
going solo versus deciding
yourself what needs to be done.
Well, this is hopeless.
Guess I'll have to play
the role of teacher.
First, name me our top
priority in this situation.
[BONDE grunts]
[BONDE]
We absolutely cannot allow
the item in the safe deposit box
to be taken.
That's our primary objective.
[MORAN]
Correct.
Now that we have it
in our possession,
we could simply leave the
scene and walk out of here.
Should we?
We can't. If we leave
things the way they are,
when the robbers wake up,
they might start executing
the hostages.
[MORAN]
So what do you propose?
We kill them?
Out of the question.
We must avoid all causalities.
Otherwise, the Yard
will be all over the scene.
There's also the risk
Holmes might get involved.
Even if it were
mere coincidence,
we want to avoid the fact
a member of the Moriarty
family was ever present.
We need to bring a swift
end to the robbery--
one which avoids
Holmes's detection.
So why don't you tell us
what we should do, then.
Subdue the robbers
in such a way
that nobody knows we were
the ones responsible.
Then, release the hostages.
[MORAN chuckles]
Right.
Now that we've sorted that out,
you're free to do
whatever you'd like
as long as it doesn't
deviate from the primary goal.
[BONDE gasps]
Whatever I'd like?
The vault room is secure,
so that could be of use.
There are four hostiles
in the main hall.
Speaking of, it's
large and they're spread out.
Taking them down undetected
will be quite a challenge.
He means impossible.
[BONDE chuckles] Not for me.
If I have carte blanche
in this situation,
I'll cash that check.
It may be unorthodox.
But then again,
I never did fit one mould.
[MORAN grunts]
I've an idea how to get out
of this. Care to work with me?
[BANK CUSTOMERS whimper]
[ROBBER 15A] Ugh!
What is taking them so long?
Oi, somebody go see
what's-- [grunts]
[BANK CUSTOMERS gasp]
[ROBBER 15B]
Uh, what's happening?
[ROBBER 15C]
Gunfire? From where?
[BONDE]
One!
Two!
Three!
Four!
Five!
Six!
Seven!
Eight!
[ROBBER 15E groans]
[BONDE] Wake up!
Open your eyes, officer!
[grunts, gasps]
Wow, I've never
seen such heroism!
As expected from one of the
Yard's vaunted officers.
[GEOFF]
Wh--
I'm responsible for that?!
[GEOFF] It's so strange,
I can't recall a thing.
[BONDE]
A heart-stopping feat like that,
it's only natural
you wouldn't remember.
[CUSTOMER 15A] Geoff,
you saved all of our lives.
[BANK CUSTOMERS chatter,
clapping]
[chuckles]
Handling these amateurs
was child's play!
It's like I told you,
any criminal who
steps foot in here
will have to answer to the law!
[MORAN] Quite the ingenious
plan you came up with, Bonde.
Shoot out the lights,
then use the muzzle flashes.
I couldn't have
done it on my own.
Thanks for having
my back. I mean it.
[MORAN chuckles]
Took all four of them out
in a large hall
without a single death.
Then afterwards,
pinned the whole act
on that buffoon of a cop.
I'd say you've
earned passing marks.
We'll have to do
this again, Bonde.
Cheers to our first
successful mission.
Not too much, though.
[BONDE chuckles]
A word, Louis?
Those bank robbers,
I recognized them.
It might've been staged--
the entire thing.
You suspect they were
hired to bring us closer
to Mister Bonde?
Come on!
[LOUIS] Indeed.
Furthermore, I bet I know who
employed them.
[MORAN] You fiend!
Thanks for saving me a drop!
Forget initiative--you
need to learn some manners!
[JACK] What's this? Who's
shouting about manners?
Surely, not Moran.
What? Old man!
Pardon, I mean Master.
Master?
[JACK]
Ahh, this brings back memories.
Who is this gentleman?
That's Jack Renfield.
That's not his only name.
During the First
Anglo-Afghan War,
he was Britain's master
of close-quarters combat--
a man to be feared.
They called him...
...Jack the Ripper.
[MORAN]
Don't be fooled.
This is the actual
"Jack the Ripper."
The real one?
Then you mean the serial killer
is some sort of imposter?
They must be.
True, he went by the nickname
"Jack the Ripper" at one point,
but that was over
half a century ago.
Isn't that right, Master?
[laughs]
I suppose they did call me
that dreadful name
when you were but a lad.
Really? You're going to start
playing the old man card now?
Obviously, William
has called you in
regarding the
Whitechapel murders.
Otherwise, you wouldn't be here.
[WILLIAM]
Sorry.
That's not quite it.
We wake you? You ought
to be getting more rest.
[WILLIAM] No, I need to
inform you all of some details.
[footsteps]
[JACK] It has been far
too long, Master William.
Whatever you request of this
old man in his waning years,
he'll happily oblige.
In fact, I would be
more than grateful.
You needn't be so formal.
Feel free to call me "Young
Will," as you always have.
By the way.
[WILLIAM] Whilst I was sleeping,
you entered the room
and pinched my cheek.
Didn't you?
[laughs] How'd you
know about that?
After all these years,
still the same!
Well, then?
You must've summoned the old
man for an important reason.
[WILLIAM]
Yes.
As you're well aware,
there's a serial killer
loose in Whitechapel.
Claiming credit for the murders
under the maestro's old handle.
In short,
this vile butcher has
besmirched Jack's good name,
and therefore needs
to be dispatched.
Jack sought my assistance
as a crime consultant.
I consented to work with him.
And so,
I sent you to retrieve his
tools of the trade in advance.
Speaking of which, your errand--
I trust it was uneventful?
[BOTH grunt]
[MORAN chuckles] Yeah, sure.
Nothing we couldn't handle.
Agreed, Bonde?
Completely.
I am curious, though.
You refer to him as Maestro.
What sort of relationship
do you all share?
[LOUIS] Ah. We haven't yet told
you that part yet, have we?
After the events of the fire,
the three of us went to stay
at the residence
of Lord Rockwell,
who served as our
guardian for a time.
[LOUIS] And the butler of
that estate was Maestro Jack.
[knocking]
[JACK grunts]
Come in.
[JACK]
Well, who have we here?
The lads from the
House of Moriarty.
Tell me, how can I
be of service to you?
[WILLIAM]
Pardon, Jack Renfield.
But we have an earnest
request to make of you.
Request? Please, name it.
Based on my observations,
it's clear you're former
British military--
a crackerjack soldier who
served in Afghanistan.
[JACK grunts]
[JACK]
How could he know all that?
Surely not through
observation alone.
[WILLIAM]
Additionally,
my research shows
you've earned a moniker--
"Jack the Ripper."
On the battlefield,
you were feared by both
friend and foe alike.
[JACK chuckles] Regarding my
past, I've only let the lord
of the estate in on my
little secret. Tell me.
What is your request?
How may this feeble
old man be of service to you?
It's a brutal world.
If we want to be able to
survive on our own,
we need you to teach us
how to protect ourselves.
And how would I be
able to help with that?
[JACK gasps]
[JACK cackles]
What serious lads!
Very well, I'll teach
you everything
you'll need to
protect yourselves,
or more accurately speaking,
the skills that're
required to kill a man.
[WILLIAM chuckles]
[LOUIS] The maestro taught
us all manner of lessons.
And if it were not
for his tutelage,
this entire organization
would have never existed.
I understand now.
After we reveal the true
identity of the killer,
it will become
clear whether or not
they have any
connection to the maestro.
We will purge society of this
paltry Jack the
Ripper imitation,
ending the scandal and
restoring the maestro's name.
Besides,
it's impossible to overlook
their taste in victims--
how they choose to
prey upon the weak.
Old Whitechapel.
It looks the same, sadly.
[gun fires]
Gunshots?
- -[CITIZEN 15A] Sod off!
- -[CITIZEN 15B] Get out!
The bloody Yard's
not welcome 'ere!
Don't need rats like you
to help keep our streets safe!
[CITIZEN 15D]
You watch!
We're gonna find and
kill that murderer ourselves!
Doesn't make sense
for the residents
to be facing off
against the Yard.
They're after the
same man, right?
It's our job to
protect the citizenry!
We'll handle
the killer, not you!
Well, when do you
plan on startin'?!
You lot haven't investigated
anything so far!
As if you've ever thought
of us as "the citizenry"!
[grunts]
[POLICEMEN gasp]
This whole district's a
powder keg about to explode.
You're right; one false
step is all it will take.
And then the match
will be struck.
This killer has put the
entire town on the precipice.
The battle for Whitechapel
is about to begin.
[ARTERTON grunts]
Those pests think
they run the show?!
Listen, men.
Starting now, Scotland Yard's
immediate priority
is the disarmament of
the Vigilance Committee!
[LESTRADE]
Chief Inspector Arterton!
I believe the safety of the
citizens ought to
come before anything else!
We should focus all our efforts
on arresting the murderer!
[footsteps]
[ARTERTON]
Is that so, Lestrade?
Listen, you clearly don't
understand the nature of things.
It makes no difference
how many dregs
that maniac carves up;
let him kill them all!
But the second those
vigilantes stage an uprising,
it will be too late!
Or have you forgotten
about Bloody Sunday,
when the paupers
clashed with us?!
A blight on our record and
mistake that can't be repeated.
Seriously, who cares
how many whores get killed?!
Disarm the Vigilance
Committee like I ordered!
[INSPECTORS]
Sir!
[LESTRADE grunts]
Quite the show.
I've never seen Chief Inspector
Arterton in such an uproar.
Seems the commissioner--
no, even the interior minister
must be putting a lot
of pressure on him.
Paterson, I'm stepping
out for an hour or so.
Handle any emergencies
that come up, would you?
As if you need to ask.
We're chums, aren't we?
Interesting.
What's that you're
all looking at?
[WILLIAM] Investigative reports
from our man inside the Yard.
[BONDE (ADLER)] An inside man?
Indeed, and the two of you
will most likely be
working together soon.
Really? I can't wait.
Based on these reports,
Scotland Yard's not even
close to arresting a suspect.
[WILLIAM] Yes. They seem
fixated on the theory
this is work of a single
psychotic killer,
but I'm able to more clearly see
the full scope of these murders.
[GROUP grunts]
[WILLIAM]
We're going to teach
these phony Jack
the Rippers a lesson.
Soon they'll discover who the
real devils around here are.
[JACK] Next time on
Moriarty the Patriot  :
"The Phantom of
Whitechapel Act Two."